Discussion

As it mentioned in domain, there are number of courses which are mandatory and assigned by each Program, so we add a relation called ProgramAssignCourse with an attribute called type that shows the mandatory courses that are allocated by each program. This is the same for relation between Branch and Course which is called BranchAssignCourse. According to domain each program assigns mandatory courses and also has recommended one that could be selected by students. An attribute called type here shows whether a course is mandatory or recommended.

Since not all courses have number of restrictions, the courses which have it could be defined as a special kind of course which ISA course, and each restrictedCourse has an extra attributes as ‘#restriction’. The waitingList is only applicable for those kind of courses. For the schema, we choose E-R approach,which only contains the key attribute of its super entity. When it comes to the classification, since not all courses have been classified and some courses have more than one classifications, we introduce an entity as classification which has type of ‘Mathematical’, ’Research’ and ‘Seminar’. The relationship ‘classified’ connect the classification with courses.

In addition to that, the student graduation is not directly shown in the diagram, since the ER diagram is not possible to show all the constraints in the description, but whether a student fulfill the requirements for graduation could be known by calculating whether the student has passed the mandatory courses assigned by his/her Branch or Program and the extra credit requirements needed for graduation. Whether a course is passed or not could be shown by grade, which is categorized into  'U', '3', '4', '5' , ‘U’ means not passed while the other grades denote various degrees of success. And the student is not allowed to register to a course which he has enrolled in with a grade equal or more than ‘3’.The system should also allow a student to unregister a course before he enrolls in it.